博偉國際
三星影片公司
試金石影片公司
發行
星 河 戰 隊
聯邦電視網
加入軍隊
全世界的青年男女
Young people from all over the globe...
為全人類的未來奮戰
are joining up to fight for the future.
- 我要出力 - 我要出力
- I'm doing my part. - I'm doing my part.
- 我要出力 - 我也要出力
- I'm doing my part. - I'm doing my part too.
他們全在出力 你呢?
They're doing their part, are you?
加入機動部隊 拯救世界
Join the Mobile Infantry and save the world.
入伍就能獲得公民權
Service guarantees citizenship.
"你想知道更多嗎? "
"蟲族隕石"
蟲族隕石再度侵犯地球
The bugs send another meteor our way...
這次我們有所準備
but this time we're ready.
地球的防衛日益精良
Planetary defences are better than ever.
"你想知道更多嗎? "
蟲族隕石來自克蘭達夫星球
Klendathu, source of the bug meteor attacks...
環繞著雙子星系統運行
orbits a twin star system whose brutal gravitational forces...
附近的帶狀行星群帶來
produce an unlimited supply of bug meteorites...
大量的蟲族隕石
in the form of this asteroid belt.
為了捍衛太陽系
To ensure the safety of our solar system...
必須消滅克蘭達夫星球
Klendathu must be eliminated.
現在從克蘭達夫星球現場
We break net now and take you live to Klendathu...
轉播這場大戰
where the invasion has begun.
衛星連線 2...1...開始
EXQ uplink on two, one. You're on.
- 我們剛降落在... - 快 快 快!
- We'vejust landed here on what cap troopers... - Move, move, move!
- 被稱為大K星的戰場 - 快! 走! 走!
- are calling Big K, - Come on! Move, move!
- 第六機動部隊正展開攻擊 - 快!
- with the 6th Mobile Infantry Division! - Come on!
這醜陋的星球全是大蟲
It's an ugly planet, a bug planet!
威脅人類的生存
A planet hostile to life as we know it!
救命啊!
Help me!
- 快走 快 快 - 快!
- Come on! Go, go, go! - Keep moving!
快離開這
Get out of here now!
基頓 不!
Kitten, no!
"一年前"
瑞哥...瑞哥...
Rico. Rico.
瑞哥!
Rico!
專心點
Pay attention.
對不起 瑞斯加科先生
Sorry, Mr Rasczak.
總而言之
Let's sum up.
今年我們談過民主制度失敗的原因
This year we explored the failure of democracy...
- 壞傢伙 - 社會學家...
- Bad boy. - how the social scientists brought our world...
讓世界陷入混亂
to the brink of chaos.
我們談到退伍軍人終於接管統治...
We talked about the veterans, how they took control...
長久以來使得地球得以安定
and imposed the stability that has lasted for generations since.
這些是事實
You know these facts...
讓你們學到了什麼?
but have I taught you anything of value this year?
我問你為何只有公民才能投票？
You. Why are only citizens allowed to vote?
這是一種獎賞
It's a reward
那是為聯邦政府服務得到的獎勵
what the Federation gives you for doing Federal Service.
不對 不對
No. No.
賜與的權利沒有價值
Something given has no value.
投票權是政治權
Look, when you vote, you are exercising political authority.
那就是力量 力量就是暴力
You're using force. And force, my friends, is violence,
暴力是所有權力的來源
the supreme authority from which all other authority is derived.
我媽媽說暴力解決不了問題
Uh, my mother always said violence never solves anything.
真的?
Really?
我真好奇廣島的先民會說什麼
I wonder what the city fathers of Hiroshima would say about that.
你來回答
You.
他們什麼都不能說，因為廣島被炸了
They probably wouldn't say anything. Hiroshima was destroyed.
沒錯
Correct.
歷史證明赤裸裸的...
Naked force has resolved more issues...
暴力解決許多問題
throughout history than any other factor.
暴力解決不了問題的論調...
The contrary opinion, that violence never solves anything,
...只是自欺欺人的想法
is wishful thinking at its worst.
忘記歷史教訓的人將付出代價
People who forget that always pay.
瑞哥 在道德上...
Rico, what's the moral difference, if any...
公民和平民有何不同?
between a civilian and a citizen?
公民接受政府賦與的責任...
A citizen accepts personal responsibility for the safety...
並且誓死捍衛地球
of the body politic, defending it with his life.
- 平民則不然 - 標準答案
- A civilian does not. - The exact words of the text.
可是你瞭解嗎? 你相信嗎?
But do you understand it? Do you believe it?
- 不知道 - 那是當然的
- I don't know. - Of course you don't.
就算是死到臨頭
I doubt anyone here would recognize civic virtue...
你們都不瞭解公民的責任
if it reached up and bit you in the ass.
第三節下課 第四節五分鐘後上課
別在這
Not here.
來吧 咱們去看數學課的成績
Come on, let's see if they posted the math final.
- 瑞哥 贏得了泰斯拉隊嗎? - 我們會痛宰他們
- Rico, we gonna take Tesla? - We're gonna kill 'em.
記住 畢業生都得填寫710表格
Remember, all graduating seniors must fill out a 710 form.
星艦軍校最重視數學成績
First thing Fleet Academy looks at is your math scores.
祝我好運
Wish me luck.
"艾邦妮茲 數學97%"
- 好傢伙 - 幹得好
- Way to go. - Good job.
該你了 等一下
Your turn. Hold on.
我去找馬可 他姐姐在星際艦隊
I want to talk to Marco. His sister's at Fleet.
- 馬可 - 嗨 卡門
- Marco. - Hi, Carmen.
- 你姐有消息嗎? - 她當上飛行員
- What do you hear about Roxy? - She made pilot.
"瑞哥 數學35%"
35% 真棒
Thirty-five percent. Very nice.
大伙看 35%
Look at that. Thirty-five percent, ladies and gentlemen.
分數真高
Big numbers.
- 卡爾 - 抱歉
- Carl. - Sorry.
你們還沒上床吧 別騙我
So, you haven't done it yet, have you? Don't lie.
我並不急
I'm not in any hurry.
- 有人在等你 - 那麼?
- Others are waiting. - And?
- 你能猜到她在想什麼? - 不必猜
- Did you read her mind? - Don't have to.
她在想什麼很明顯
It's pretty clear what she wants.
是呀 我要的是卡門
Yeah, but I want Carmen.
- 你想得要死 - 再見 馬可
- Aw, you got it bad. - Bye, Marco.
別忘了下午的事
Hey, don't forget about this afternoon.
他老是為了親你芳澤耽誤正事
He's always late when he walks you home to fish for a kiss.
快走開
Get out of here.
- 馬可的姐姐當上飛行員 - 你也會的
- Marco's sister made pilot. - So will you.
想想看 如果要駕駛五十萬噸重的星際戰艦
I mean, imagine flying a half a million tons of starship.
你就得勇氣十足
You gotta have nerves of steel.
當然 你有沒有種呢?
Yeah, you do. Let's see how yours hold up.
開始吧
You may begin.
這只是一隻蟲 戴上護鏡
Aw, come on, it's just a bug. You better put your goggles on.
只是一隻蟲?
"Just a bug."
人類自以為是大自然主宰者
We humans like to think we are nature's finest achievement.
其實並不然
I'm afraid it just isn't true.
這只甲蟲遠比人類優良
This Arkellian sand beetle is superior in many ways.
它的繁殖力很強 沒有私心...
It reproduces in vast numbers, has no ego...
不會恐懼 絕不怕死
has no fear, doesn't now about death...
它是蟲族社會完美的一份子
and so is the perfect selfless member of society.
人類創造了藝術數學...
But humans have created art, mathematics...
和星際旅行
and interstellar travel.
沒錯 不過千萬別自大
True. But before you let that go to your head...
就拿阿瑞克尼蟲族來說
take the example of the Arachnids...
那是高度進化的社會
a highly evolved insect society.
以人類的標準來說它們的智慧很低
By human standards, they are relatively stupid...
它們卻有數百萬年的進化史
but their evolution stretches over millions of years...
- 現在 - 這兒 拿著
- and now... - Here, take this.
它們能夠把胚種
they can colonize planets...
送入太空佔領別的星球
by hurling their spore into space.
應該找到了
Okay, I think we got it.
這是心臟
That's the heart.
這是胃囊
And here's the stomach.
這算勇氣十足?
Nerves of steel, huh?
"不符合"
別費力去想 憑你的直覺想像畫面
Don't think about it. Just go on instinct.
試著將它形象化
Try to visualize it.
我看到黑桃A
I see the ace of spades.
統計學上的概率上來說
You know, statistically speaking,
到現在你就算瞎猜也該不小心猜到了吧!
you should have accidentally guessed right by now.
- 再試一次 - 我不會心靈感應 而且運氣也很背
- Try another. - So my psychic abilities are zero and I'm unlucky.
這跟運氣無關
No, luck's not a factor.
有些人就是特別靈敏
No one really knows why some people are sensitive and some aren't.
誰知道? 也許這是人類下一步的進化
Who knows? Maybe it's a new stage of human evolution.
所以才有這種研究
That's why they do these kind of Federal studies.
西哈諾 該死 暫停
What... Cyrano... Oh, shit. Time out.
它只是不甘寂寞
Oh, he just wants some attention.
你從不陪它玩
You don't play with him any more.
西哈諾...
Cyrano.
去煩我老媽去
Go bug Mom, Cyrano.
你是怎麼做的?
How do you make him do that?
我讓它覺得我媽腳上有食物
Oh, I gave him the impression there's a grub crawling up my mom's leg.
它非吃到不可
He's on a mission to go eat it.
滾開 別碰我
Ow! Oh! Get out! Get off my leg! Oh! Carl!
你最好別在我身上用心靈感應這招
I sure hope you don't do anything like that to me.
別怕 對人類我沒轍...暫時不行
Don't be afraid. Can't do human. Yet.
好啊
Yeah!
好!
All right!
- 好啊! - 老虎隊得分
- Yeah! Yeah! - Touchdown Tigers.
現在的比數是41比38
And the score is now 41-38.
老虎隊領先 只勝兩局
Tigers lead with 2. 46 remaining...
這堿O布宜諾斯艾利斯球場
here at the Buenos Aires Sports Arena.
巨人隊喊暫停
Time out Giants.
- 你還好吧? - 好多了
- Are you all right? - Much better.
- 現在 - 好
- Now. - Good.Yeah!
好 上啊!
All right! Way to go, team!
嗨 你的頭盔
Hey! Your helmet.
球賽後你要幹嘛?
So, what are you doing after the game?
大家都要參加舞會 你去嗎?
Well, everyone's going to the dance, aren't you?
不清楚 今晚是我當平民的最後一夜
I don't know. It's my last night as a civilian.
- 上 12號! 沖! - 明天我就要去特雷斯卡瓦
- Come on, number 12! Let's go! - Ship out for Tereshkova tomorrow.
- 你要去星艦軍校? - 嗯
- You're going to the Fleet Academy? - Uh-huh.
我也想去
That's where I want to go!
十二號 上場了
Come on, number 12! Let's play ball!
別打我女友的主意
Don't get any ideas about my girlfriend!
情場如戰場
All is fair in love and war.
- 巨人隊! 巨人隊! - 強尼 加油
- Giants! Giants! -Johnny! Yeah!
嘿 好啊!
Hey, yeah!
巨人隊以43分領先 離終場只剩22秒鐘
Giants leading 43-41. Just over 22 seconds remaining.
老虎隊的時間所剩不多
- Yeah! - All right, let's go.
艾文 拉森 擋住攻擊
Irvin, Lathom, cover the rush.
派瑞做假動作 勃迪跑遠點
Perry, fake left. Bertolli, you go long.
瑞哥 空翻六,三洞 懂嗎?  瑞哥?
Rico, flip six, three hole. Got it? Hey, Rico?
- 嘿! - 什麼?
- Hey! - What?
專心點 空翻六,三洞  懂嗎?
You're drifting! Flip six, three hole, on one! Got it?
- 儘管把球傳給我 蒂絲 - 準備好了?
-Just throw me the ball, Diz. - Ready? Break!
好! 走 走!
Yeah! Go, go, go!
好!
All right!
耶!
Yeah!
得分了 比賽結束
He's in there. It's over.
你一下子就長這麼大了
Who said you could grow up so fast, huh?
媽 別這樣
Mom, don't get mushy.
這是今天寄來的
This came for you today.
是你要的吧?
I presume, at your request.
我有很多朋友都要服役
A lot of my friends are doing Federal Service.
你不是想報名入伍吧?
Well, you're not thinking of applying?
你瘋啦?
Have you lost your mind?
我就算是要挨鞭刑也不准你去自毀前程
I'd rather take ten lashes in Public Square than see you ruin your life.
這是志願服役
It's a term of service.
不是從軍
It's not a career.
我只想一個人出去...
I just want to get out on my own...
見識一下銀河系風光
see the galaxy for a couple years.
強尼 當兵會死人的
Johnny, people get killed in the Federal Service.
是誰把你說動的? 是那個老師 對吧?
Who gave you this idea? It's that teacher, isn't it?
他叫什麼? 你應該知道
What's his name? You know the one I'm talking about.
- 瑞斯加科先生 - 瑞斯加科?
- Mr Rasczak. - Rasczak?
這名字真可笑 法律應該...
Silly name. There should be a law against...
禁止學校召募新兵
using a school as a recruiting station.
瑞斯加科不會這麼做
No, Rasczak doesn't do that at all.
其實他反對學生從軍
He sort of discourages you.
那就好
Well, that's good.
你得上哈佛 沒什麼好說的
'Cause you're going to Harvard, and that's the end of it.
這是我的決定 不是你的
It's my decision, not yours.
- 你真這麼想? - 別吵了
- Oh, is that how it is, huh? - Wait, you two.
我和你父親要給你個驚喜
Uh, Dad and I have a surprise for you that will settle this.
你猜得到嗎?
Can you guess what it is?
猜不到
No.
你想見識銀河系風光
You wanted to see the galaxy?
到土星外環旅行如何?
How about a trip to the Outer Rings?
西格瑪海灘
Zegema Beach. Huh?
我一直想去那兒
I've always wanted to go there.
很好 就這麼說定了
Good, good. Then it's all settled.
∮  into it, into your head ∮
∮ save it sell one ∮
∮ mix it hang these ∮
∮ leftover waste ∮
別走開
Sure. Don't go away.
我想找瑞斯加科先生
I'm just gonna go see Mr Rasczak.
瑞哥 想跳舞嗎?
Hey, Rico, do you want to dance?
蒂絲 我答應卡門
Actually, Diz, I promised Carmen...
真可惜 她不在
Aw, come on. Too bad for her if she's not around.
真傷心 過了今晚...
You know, it's sad. After tonight, most of us...
我們恐怕不會再見面
probably won't see each other again.
你要替巴西隊打球嗎? (Rio de Janeiro里約熱內盧)
So, you still gonna play for Rio?
是呀,除非東京隊要我當開球手
Yeah, looks like. Unless Tokyo lets me start.
誰搶到你就走運了
Well, anyone who gets you is lucky.
我們怎麼沒成為一對?
Johnny, how come we never got together?
我們不能只當朋友嗎?
Can't we just be friends, Diz?
好
Sure.
- 謝謝 - 晚上好
- Thank you. - Good night.
蒂絲 我想找瑞斯加科先生
Look, Diz, I want to talk to Mr Rasczak.
你最好趕快去
Well, you better hurry up if you want to catch him.
你是我最好的朋友
You're the best.
瑞斯加科先生
Mr Rasczak!
- 什麼事? 瑞哥 - 我要謝謝你
- What is it, Rico? - I want to thank you.
我最喜歡你的課
Your class was the best one I had this year.
我只希望你能有所收穫
Well, it's really not my job to please. I just hope you learned something.
我想入伍
Well, I want to join up.
我覺得我有成為公民的勇氣
I think I got what it takes to be a citizen.
很好 去試吧
Good for you. Go find out.
我父母卻反對
Well, my parents are against it.
我知道這是我的選擇
And I know it's my choice.
我在想...
I was wondering...
你若是我 你會怎麼做?
what would you do if you were me?
能決定自己的前程
Figuring things out for yourself...
才是真正的自由
is the only freedom anyone really has.
珍惜這自由
Use that freedom.
自己決定吧
Make up your own mind, Rico.
∮ ah-oh ∮
∮ but I have not been to paradise ∮
∮ ah-lay-oh ∮
∮ no, I have not been to paradise ∮
∮ watch the days go by ∮
∮ all is well ∮
別亂講
Don't exaggerate.
是真的 你的眼睛好美
I'm serious. I think you have really beautiful eyes.
- 你瞭解? - 強尼
- You know? -Johnny.
這是山德
Uh, this is Zander.
我們在球場上較過勁
Yeah, we know each other from the game.
- 你不介意吧? - 不介意 我們贏了
- No hard feelings? - No, none at all. We won.
來吧 卡門 最後一支舞
Come on, Carmen. It's the last dance.
也許我在軍校會見到你
Well, maybe I'll see you at the Academy.
是啊 也許會吧
Yeah. Who knows?
祝你好運
Good luck.
山德也要當飛行員
Zander's going for pilot too.
你們真是絕配 卡門
You two have so much in common.
強尼·瑞哥 你在吃醋嗎?
Johnny Rico, are you jealous?
也許吧
Well, maybe.
你不必吃醋
You don't have to be jealous.
嗨 嗨...快分開 你們兩個
Hey, hey, break it up, you two.
要親熱就到別的地方
There's a place for that sort of thing.
我考慮好了 我要入伍
I've been thinking, and I'm gonna do it, Carmen.
我要加入聯邦軍隊
I'm gonna go for Federal Service.
太好了
That's great.
我和卡爾明天登記 和我們一起去吧
Carl and I are signing up tomorrow. Come with us.
我會的
I will.
∮ walk about watch the days go by ∮
我父親今晚不在家
My father's not home tonight.
∮ all is well ∮
∮ talk about watch the days go by ∮
∮ twenty-third century guys ∮
∮ all is well ∮
我莊嚴宣誓
I do now, of my own free will...
我們已被告知這一宣誓的意義和責任
after having been duly advised and warned...
這一切完全出於自願
of the meaning and consequences of this oath...
我志願入伍
enrol in the Federal Service...
至少服役兩年
for not less than two years...
若是聯邦需要我時
and as much longer as may be required...
繼續在部隊效力
by the needs of the Federation.
- 完了? - 謝謝
- All set? - Thank you.
又來一批新兵
Fresh meat for the grinder, eh?
- 你們的成績如何? - 我要當飛行員
- So, how'd you kids do? - I'm gonna be a pilot.
很好 我們很需要飛行員
Well, good for you. We need all the pilots we can get.
- 你被分派到研發部門嗎? - 沒有
- Hey, did you get starside R and D? - No.
- 不是吧? - 我要到戰略理論部
- I don't believe it. - I got Games and Theory.
戰略理論?
Games and Theory?
- 那是軍事情報部 - 嗯
- That's military intelligence. - Yeah.
好傢伙 卡爾
Way to go, Carl.
下次見面我就得向你敬禮
Next time we meet, I'll probably have to salute you.
嗯
Hmm.
你呢 孩子?
How about you, son?
- 機動部隊 長官 - 很好
- Infantry, sir. - Good for you.
機動部隊讓我成為現在這個樣子
Mobile Infantry made me the man I am today.
新兵必須在二十四小時內到聯邦運送站報到
All recruits must report to the Federal Transportation Hub within 24 hours.
歡迎加入聯邦軍隊的行列
Welcome to the adventure of Federal Service.
咱們一起發誓
Let's make a vow.
不管怎樣 我們永遠是朋友
No matter what, we'll always be friends.
我同意
I'll go for that.
我們恐怕不會再見面
Well, chances are we'll never see each other again.
分隔幾百萬光年的距離
We'll be millions of light-years away from each other.
不過 好呀 有何不可?
But, uh, yeah, sure. Why not?
你給我去辦退役
You'll resign, and that's all there is to it.
雖然很沒面子 不過也只能這樣了
It may look bad, but if that's the worst you suffer, then that's fine.
- 我不要退役 - 你一定要
- I won't quit! - I'm telling you, you will.
你不能入伍 你要去渡假
You're not going back. You're going on vacation!
我不去渡假
I am not going on vacation!
我要當公民
I want to be a citizen.
這是我的決定
It's my decision. I made it.
你走出去找就不認你這兒子
You walk out that door, you are cut off, young man.
懂嗎?
You understand me?
好吧 我不要你了
All right, that's it! You are cut off!
你這是何必呢?
Johnny, why won't you change your mind?
當公民這麼重要嗎?
Does citizenship mean that much to you?
當然重要
Well, yeah, sure.
希望如此
Well, I hope so.
希望你別為了以為穿制服很美的蠢姑娘...
I hope you don't ruin your life over some silly little girl...
而葬送了自己的前程
who wants to look handsome in a uniform.
- 別以這種方式談論卡門 - 強尼
- Don't talk about Carmen that way! -Johnny.
請注意 13-A現在出站
Your attention, please. Outbound troops 13-A...
東西都帶好了?
Do you have everything?
好了
Great.
強尼
Johnny
- 你遲到了 - 我父親幫我收拾行李
- You're late. - My dad had to help me pack.
他突然怕再也見不到我
Suddenly he's afraid he's never gonna see me again or something.
他真好 不過很費時間
It was sweet, but it took forever.
不管怎樣我猜我準備好了
Oh. Anyway, I guess I'm ready to go.
我也是 我的行李都在身上了
Yeah, me too. I'm wearing everything I own.
我很遺憾你的父母反對
I'm sorry your parents were mad.
管它呢 反正...
Who cares? The Federation will give me...
這兩年軍隊會養我 對吧?
everything I need for the next two years, right?
- 你和卡爾聯絡過嗎? - 有 他早上就走了
- You talk to Carl? - Yeah, he left this morning.
- 他不能說去哪 - 能夠入伍我好興奮
- Couldn't say where. - Oh, it's exciting, going away.
我也很害怕 你不會嗎?
But I'm scared. Aren't you?
我會很想你
I'm gonna miss you.
我也會想你
I'm gonna miss you too.
我愛你
I love you.
前往特雷斯卡瓦的新兵準備啟程
Outbound group 94B to Tereshkova...
我該走了
That's me.
說一次 試試看
Just say it once. Try it on for size.
我愛你
I love you.
別忘了寫信給我
Don't forget to write.
我不會忘的
I won't.
"聯邦電視網"
"世界團結一致"
全自動步槍 誰想拿?
Fully automatic Morita. Who wants to hold it?
我! 我! 我...
Me! Me! Me! Me! Me!
公民萬歲 人民創造美好明天
Citizen rule. People making a better tomorrow.
"你想知道更多嗎? "
殺人犯今天被捕後接受審判
A murderer was captured this morning and tried today.
有罪
Guilty.
處以死刑
Sentence.: death.
今晚六點行刑 實況轉播
Execution tonight at 6.:00. All net. All channels.
你想知道更多嗎?
"你能心靈感應嗎? "
如果你覺得能
If you think you're psychic,
也許是真的
maybe you are.
各地都在進行這項研究
Federal studies are being conducted in your community.
你想知道更多嗎?
"警告"
每個小學生都知道阿瑞克尼蟲很危險
Every school kid knows that Arachnids are dangerous.
"不宜觀賞"
摩門教徒卻罔顧聯邦警告
However, Mormon extremists disregarded Federal warnings...
在蟲族隔離區建立教會
and established Fort Joe Smith deep inside the Arachnid Quarantine Zone.
不料該地區早就被別人佔領
Too late, they realized that Dantana had already been chosen by other colonists.:
阿瑞克尼蟲族
Arachnids.
你想知道更多嗎?
- 一 二 三 四! - 你們大半都...
- One, two, three, four! - Most of you will not...
熬不過魔鬼訓練
live to be in the Mobile Infantry.
因為你們都不夠強
The trouble is, you are not good enough the way you are.
手放好
Hands at your side!
抬頭挺胸
Chin up.
我是你們的教官辛姆中士
I am your senior drill instructor, Career Sergeant Zim!
小腹縮緊 雙腿併攏
Suck in that gut! Feet together!
我並不情願教你們 你們這群猿人
To think this had to happen to me. What a bunch of apes.
算了,忘了剛才那句話
No, strike that!
你們連猿人都不如
You don't rate that good.
在我的生活中還從來沒有...
Never in my life have I seen...
你覺得很好笑?
Do you think I'm funny? Do I make you laugh?
- 你覺得我是小丑嗎? - 對不起
- Do you think I'm a comedian, son? - I'm sorry.
你們隨時都要尊稱我為長官
The first words and the last words out of your stinking holes will be "Sir"!
- 明白嗎? - 長官,明白 長官
- Do you get me? - Sir, yes, sir!
看到那個軍械庫了嗎? 圍著跑一圈
You see that armoury? Run around it.
我叫你跑就跑
Run, I said! Run, run, run!
- 布隆斯基 讓他保持住! - 快! 快!
- Bronski, keep pace! - Move! Move!
什麼時候你們覺得我太狠
Now, anytime you think I'm being too tough...
什麼時候你們覺得我太不公平
anytime you think I'm being unfair...
什麼時候你們想媽媽了，那就退出
anytime you miss your mommy, quit!
填好表格、簽名、拿上行李
You sign form 1240-A, you grab your gear...
走上失敗者的路
you take a stroll down Washout Lane!
明不明白?
Do you get me?
- 長官,明白，長官! - 可悲
- Sir, yes, sir! - Pathetic!
全是一群孬種 不知道這埵釣S有好漢
I wonder if there's a handful of guts in the whole bunch of you.
誰認為他有辦法打倒我?
Now, who here thinks they got what it takes to knock me down?
長官!我覺得我能 長官
Sir! I guess maybe I do, sir!
哦! 天哪! 天哪!
Ow! God! God!
- 你沒事吧? - 長官,沒事 長官
- You all right, son? - Sir, yes, sir!
我的手好像斷了
It's my arm. I think it's broken, sir.
- 醫官! - 天哪
- Medic! - God.
痛只是是心媟Q的
Pain is in your mind!
- 下一個是誰? - 長官
- Who's next? - Sir!
新兵弗洛斯報到 長官
Recruit Flores reporting for duty, sir!
你特別要求從克倫凱特要塞轉到這部隊？
You specifically requested transfer from Fort Cronkite to this training unit?
長官,我聽說這堿O最棒的,長官!
Sir, I heard it was the best, sir!
的確是最棒的
It is the best.
你憑什麼以為自己夠資格?
But what makes you think you're good enough?
這女孩有種當班長
Now that's the kind of gal who makes squad leader.
當班長的活是我的
That's my job you're talking about.
我很想宰了辛姆中士
You know, I'd like to kill that Sergeant Zim.
- 你的態度很不好 - 小心
- Whoa, improper attitude! - Watch it.
- 這樣會被踢出去 - 再見吧
- They'll kick you out for talking like that. - Bye-bye.
你肯定會走上失敗走路
There you go down Washout Lane.
沒種就是沒種
Yup, you either got what it takes, or you don't.
- 我們在排隊 - 你也要等 王牌
- Hey, there is a line. - Wait your turn, Ace.
別緊張 小兵 反正菜都很爛
Hey, at ease, little soldier. It's all the same muck.
乖乖去排隊
Get in line like everyone else.
你這闊少爺真有種
You got some guts for a rich kid.
咱們交個朋友 如何?
I guess you and me could be buddies. What do you say?
- 真是榮幸 - 當然 我最夠朋友了
- I'm honoured. - Hey! Of course you are.
每個人都應該有個像我這樣的朋友
Everybody should have a friend like me.
王牌 到後面排隊吧
Come on, Ace. Back of the line now! Back of the line!
- 真是個混蛋 - 討厭鬼
- What a jerk, man. - Tough guy.
瑞哥 跟我一起吃飯
Hey, Rico, want to sit together?
不 謝了
No thanks, Diz.
你有什麼問題?
What's your malfunction, Rico?
你就是問題
You are.
我想一個人入伍 你卻硬要跟來
I joined up to get out on my own, and you had to tag along.
你以為我為你入伍?
You think I joined the Mobile Infantry because of you?
你敢說不是?
You saying you didn't?
嗨
Hi.
想都別想 王牌 你不行的
Forget about it, Ace. You don't stand a chance.
難道你就能當班長?
What makes you even think you're gonna make squad leader, Rico?
- 我比你有料 - 哈!
- Something I got, you don't. - Ha!
- 有錢少爺只會裝闊 - 才不
- You rich kids are all the same. - It isn't about that.
- 這得靠能力 - 嘿!
- It's about who's the best. - Hey!
第三班
Third squad!
長官 我不懂
Sir, I don't understand.
在核戰爭中何必用刀?
Who needs a knife in a nuke fight, anyway?
只要按下按鈕就行 長官
All you gotta do is push a button, sir.
暫停
Cease fire.
手放在牆上 傘兵
Put your hand on that wall, trooper.
把手放在牆上
Put your hand on that wall!
該死
Damn it.
敵人的手掌受傷就不能按鈕
The enemy cannot push a button if you disable his hand.
醫官
Medic!
我們有一個共同點
Ah, well, we all have one thing in common.
我們都蠢到要參加機動部隊
We were all stupid enough to sign up for Mobile Infantry.
- 佈雷肯瑞奇 你為何加入? - 我全家都是農夫
- Breckinridge, what's your excuse? - Oh, my family's all farmers.
我討厭務農 而機動部隊...
I hate farming. I mean, uh, Mobile Infantry...
比起來就像是在野餐
It's like pure picnic by comparison.
鄉巴佬真是又蠢又壯對不對?
All right, so they grow 'em big and dumb on the farm planet, huh?
- 而且帥! - 我就愛壯漢
- And pretty! - I like big!
- 蒂嘉娜 你呢? - 我想要從政
- Djana'D, what about you? - Oh, I'm going in for politics...
想從政就得成為公民
and, you know, you gotta be a citizen for that.
- 所以我就來了 - 你想負起責任
- So here I am. - Ah, you want some responsibility.
- 對 - 蘇傑米 接著說吧
- Yeah. - Shujimi, come on, let's keep it goin'.
我被哈佛大學取錄
I got into Harvard, but my father says forget it.
可是我老爸嫌學費太貴
It's gonna cost an arm and a leg, you know?
只要服役
So, if I serve,
就能賺取學費
Federation pays my way.
我想生孩子
I want to have babies.
公民比較容易申請執照
You know, it's a lot easier to get a licence if you've served.
- 然後呢... - 我要當職業軍官
- So... - I'm going career.
按步就班升上去
Officer's training. All the way.
未來的星際元帥 瑞哥 該你了
Future Sky Marshal. All right, Rico, your turn.
不要多管閒事
Who asked you to be so nosy?
怎麼? 我是壞人嗎? 我想當作家
What? I'm the-the bad guy? I'm gonna be a writer, you know?
當然能管閒事
A writer's got a right to be nosy.
弗洛雷斯 你和瑞哥都來自布宜諾斯艾利斯
Hey, Flores, you know Rico from Buenos Aires.
- 他為什麼入伍? - 哦
- What's his story? - Oh, uh,
他是為了一個女孩子
he's here because of a girl.
瑞哥 大情聖
Oh, Rico! Lover boy!
- 他讓我感到興奮 - 他一定會打你
- He's getting me excited. - He's gonna blow.
為了你嗎?
Is it you?
這是我們的宿舍 很簡陋 不過是我的家
This is where we live. It's not much, but it's home.
這是我的床鋪 我每晚都夢到你
Right there, that's my bunk, where I dream about you every night.
訓練很辛苦
Boot's pretty tough.
有時我很灰心
Sometimes I think I won't make it.
不過我一想到你就會更努力
But then I think about what you're doing, and I try harder.
- 嘿 你介意嗎? - 努力點 寶貝
- Hey, guys! Do you mind? - Try harder, baby, try harder!
誰知道? 也許我會成為班長
Who knows? They might even make me squad leader.
我得上床了
Uh-oh, I better pack it in.
我愛你 寶貝 我愛你!
Oh, I love you, baby, I love you!
- 寫信給我 - 我是如此愛你
- Write me! - I love you so much
- 我要殺了你 - 我是如此愛你
- I'm gonna kill you guys! - I love you so much
- 再見 記得寫信 - 再見!
- Bye! Write me. - Bye!
五分鐘後繞行月球 艾邦妮茲
Orbit in five, Ibanez.
先到先飛
First one there gets to fly.
- 關閉艙門 - 等一下
- Locking it down. - Wait! Wait!
別讓艾邦妮茲駕駛 她太瘋狂了
Oh, no. Not Ibanez again. She's crazy!
準備 發射
Ready, go!
好!
Yeah!
伸出機翼
Deploying wings.
你幹嘛這麼開心?
How come you're in such a good mood, huh?
今天我要開戰艦
'Cause today I get to fly that.
飛行受訓人員艾邦妮茲報到
Pilot Trainee Ibanez reporting for duty, ma'am.
坐在副駕駛座
Take the number two chair, Ibanez.
- 是的 女士 - 看見啦?
- Yes, ma'am. - You see that?
- 辨識身份 - 艾邦妮茲 T325A 正確
- Identify. - Ibanez, T-3 25-A, clear.
你在這兒幹嘛?
What are you doing here?
我要教你駕駛這艘戰艦
I'm the guy whose gonna teach you to fly this crate.
助理教官
Oh, Assistant Instructor.
我該尊稱你長官嗎?
Should I call you "sir"?
- 我下命令才要 - 準備起飛
- Only when I give you an order. - Prepare for departure.
真奇怪,沒想到我們會再見面
It's amazing, us running into each other like this.
- 也許是命中注定 - 也許不是
- Maybe it's fate. - Maybe not.
我聽說有個女孩很優秀
Heard about this crazy girl coming through the Academy.
她是天生好手 只是有點野
Solid math, a little wild on the stick, but a natural.
我知道是你
And when it turned out to be you,
就安排和你見面
I just made sure that we would run into each other.
楊羅傑號可以起飛
Rodger Young cleared for undocking and departure.
好了 艾邦妮茲
All right, Ibanez.
- 開出去吧 - 是的 女士
- Take her out. - Yes, ma'am.
系統正常
All systems go.
進行模擬飛行時老師都跟不上我
In simulation, my supervisors could never keep up.
這不是模擬飛行
Well, this isn't simulation any more...
小心點 軍校生
so take her out easy, cadet.
是的 長官
Yes, sir.
距離五米
Five metres from object.
距離三米
Three metres from object.
通過
Clear.
- 別超過起飛速限 - 否則呢?
- Don't exceed port speed. - Or what?
你的飛行權會被取消 還有我的
Or they revoke your flight status, and mine.
你的前途掌握在我手上
Your career is in my hands.
慢慢來 副駕駛
Steady as she goes, Number Two.
- 準備超光速飛行 - 是的
- Prepare for warp. - Yes, ma'am.
一號 計算木星航道
Number One, design for Jupiter orbit.
準備轉換超光速引擎
All crew, all sections, stand by to cut in C-drive.
五...四...
Star drive in five, four...
準備 穩定...
ready, steady...
啟動
go!
快進攻 快!
We're going in! Move!
我們衝不破防線
Man, they're defended. No way in.
- 空翻六,三洞 - 什麼?
- Flip six, three hole. - What?
你做翻跳動作就能得分
You run a flip six, three hole play, and you can score.
- 掩護我 - 好
- Cover me. - You got it.
上吧
Now!
- 謝了 哥們 - 雜種
- Thanks, buddy. - Bastard!
嗯!
Yeah!
那小子很靈活
Kid's got some moves.
讓他當班長 看看他的能耐
Give him a squad. See what he can do.
凱蒂 凱蒂
Kitty, Kitty.
我得教你們打檯球
Someone's got to teach you guys how to play some pool here.
瞧他
Look at him.
那副得意樣 真自傲
Have you ever seen anybody so pleased with himself?
辛姆一定得選個乖乖牌
Well, Zim must have had to choose someone to be his brownnose.
沒有你我就辦不到
I couldn't have done it without you, Diz.
朋友?
Friends?
朋友
Friends.
- 信來了 李維 - 我就是
- Mail call! Levy! - Yeah, that's me.
- 蘇傑米 - 在
- Shujimi! - Here.
- 瑞哥 - 在
- Rico. - Here.
- 佈雷肯瑞奇 - 嗯 在
- Breckinridge! - Yeah, right here.
- 泰勒 - 我在這兒
- Niler. - Yeah, here I am. Ah, great, my dad.
沒了 大伙
That's all, folks.
嗨 強尼
Hi, Johnny.
抱歉沒早點寫信給你
I'm sorry I haven't written you sooner, but, uh...
噢...瑞哥 你配不上她
Oh, Rico,it's been really busy.you don't deserve that!
- 噓 噓 - 他們真的在這
- Shh, shh. - They've really got us going here.
你一定當上班長
They must have made you squad leader by now.
沒有的話 叫他們來找我
And if they haven't, tell 'em to talk to me.
你瞧 找到好女人就不用愁
See? All it takes is the love of a good woman.
- 看這兒 - 別看了
- Look at that.Look at those. - Stop it.
不是很美嗎?
Isn't it beautiful?
我好愛這兒
I love it out here.
這就是問題
That's also the problem
因為 我想當職業軍人
Because I think I'm gonna go career.
我要指揮戰艦
I want to command a ship of my own.
這樣一來...
And you know...
我們就沒時間
I don't think that's gonna leave a lot of room...
交往 強尼
for you and me, Johnny.
我知道你會很失望
I know that's not what you wanted to hear.
可是
But, uh...
我得把握機會
I have to follow my heart.
對不起
I'm sorry.
寫信給我
Write me, all right?
讓我們永遠當好朋友
Write me so that I know we'll always be friends.
- 咱們還是打球吧 - 我覺得很對不起強尼
- Let's get back to the game. - I feel so sorry for Johnny.
她們總是傷透你的心
Funny how they always want to be friends...
之後還想做好朋友
after they rip your guts out, huh?
我是活該
Yeah. Well, it's what I deserve.
什麼意思?
What are you talking about?
我會入伍全是為了她
Oh, I joined up for her.
沒有她我就不會來
I wouldn't even be here if it wasn't for her.
你在說什麼? 你是靠自己當上班長
What are you talking about? You made squad leader on your own.
至少你還有我差遣
And, hey, you still got me to kick around.
好日子結束了
Fun and games are over, children.
今天要進行
You will be firing live ammunition...
實彈的模擬戰鬥
in a simulated combat environment.
你們千萬要小心進行
You will exercise extreme caution on my assault course!
- 你們都明白了嗎? - 明白 長官
- Do you get me? - Sir, yes, sir!
瑞哥 帶隊出去
Rico, take 'em out!
第一組跟我來 第二組十秒鐘後出發
First fire team with me. Next team in ten seconds.
最高分是280
Maximum score has been 280.
- 你們一定要更好 - 上吧
- I expect you to do better! - Go!
蘇傑米 趴下來
Shujimi, stay down!
該死 佈雷肯瑞奇 別擋住我
Hey! Goddam it, Breckinridge, clear my line of fire!
我的頭盔壞了
It's my helmet! It's all screwed up!
你會礙事的
You're gonna blow the score!
- 蠢蛋 - 媽的!
- Damn! - Dumb shit!
快前進 怎麼了?
Diz, stay put! What's the problem?
- 頭盔有問題 - 給我
- Damn thing keeps getting in my way! - Give it to me.
每次出錯都是你的問題
How come whenever something goes wrong, it's always you, Breckinridge?
那是因為我又蠢又壯
It must be 'cause I'm big and dumb!
沒錯
Yeah, right!
醫官
Medic!
瑞哥 你被解除班長職位
Rico, you are relieved of squad command!
是你准許新兵脫下頭盔嗎?
Rico, did you give the recruit permission to remove his helmet?
是的 長官 佈雷肯瑞奇說他的頭盔壞了
Sir, yes, sir. Breckinridge reported a helmet malfunction...
我要他拿給我看
and I asked him to show it to me, sir.
你會修理M-3型頭盔嗎?
Are you rated to repair the M-3 Tactical Helmet, Rico?
長官,不會 長官
Sir, no, sir!
那麼你為何在實彈演習時...
Then why did you order your man to remove his helmet...
叫他脫下頭盔?
during a live fire exercise?
我需要每名隊員盡全力
Sir, I needed everyone in my squad operational, sir!
我想要獲勝 長官
I wanted to win, sir!
繼續
Carry on.
軍士 我們因為此事失去兩名新兵
Sergeant, we've already lost two recruits over this incident.
你認為這個人還有前途嗎?
Do you think there's any possibility of salvaging this man?
有的 長官
Yes, sir, I do.
好吧
All right.
讓他接受行政處罰
We'll try administrative punishment.
囚犯 站住
Prisoner, halt!
用力咬
Bite down on this, son.
很有用 我很清楚
It helps. I know.
因為他指揮無能
For incompetence of command...
在實彈演習中...
for failure to abide by safety regulations...
違反安全規定...
during a live fire exercise...
因為他的疏失導致一名士兵死亡
for negligence which contributed to the death of a teammate...
新兵強尼·瑞哥
recruit trainee John Rico...
必須受刑...
is sentenced to administrative punishment.
十下鞭刑
Ten lashes.
開始行刑
You may carry out the sentence.
一...
One!
二...
Two!
三...
Three!
四...
Four!
五...
Five!
六...
Six!
七...
Seven!
八...
Eight!
九...
Nine!
十!
Ten!
謝了 你猜中我的心意
Thanks. You read my mind.
下半夜更最難熬
Oh, third watch always seems to last forever.
不一定
I don't know.
這得看你和誰一起值班
It depends on who you're spending it with.
出了問題
Something's wrong.
- 那兒 - 我重新設定航道
- There. - No, I replotted the course.
- 這樣更有效率 - 你才來了三個星期...
- It's more efficient this way. - Three weeks aboard a starship...
就想跟我比?
and you think that you can lick my navs?
儘管查
Check it.
我和達拉第艦長談過
You know, I was talking with Captain Deladier...
她說...
and, uh, she said...
別轉移話題
Don't change the subject.
我是對的嗎?
Am I right?
"新航道最佳"
是,你是對的
Yeah. Yeah. You're right.
那麼艦長怎麼說?
So, what did the captain say?
她說我們應該正式搭檔...
She thinks that we ought to team up officially...
為她服務
and crew for her.
- 你和我? - 我們是好搭檔 卡門
- You and me, huh? - We're good together, Carmen.
各方面都領先
We're way ahead of the curve in every department.
我們很有默契
I can anticipate you.
你知道我要什麼
You know what I want.
我不知道 你要什麼?
No. What do you want?
太空中有重力場
There's a gravity field out there.
- 進行掃瞄 啟動 - 那兒
- Run a scan. Sensors on. - There.
- 重力225 繼續增加... - 報告
- Gravity at 225 and rising. - Report.
船長 前方有不明物體
Captain, we're in the path of an unidentified object...
向我們快速衝來...
moving toward us at high speed.
根據資料應該是小行星
Profile suggests an asteroid, ma'am.
"撞擊警告"
- 六秒後撞擊 - 緊急閃躲動作
- Impact, six seconds! - Emergency evasion!
三...二...
Three, two,
啟動
fire!
關閉21號艙門
Close compartment 21!
從哪兒來的?
Where'd it come from?
從蟲族隔離區來的
It came out of the Arachnid Quarantine Zone, ma'am.
通訊官通知艦隊小行星接近中
Number Four, contact Fleet. Tell 'em there's a loose asteroid headed their way.
通訊失效 全都被摧毀
Communications are down, ma'am. They're gone.
- 估計損失 - 艦身受損
- Damage assessment. - Hull's compromised.
我們沒死掉真走運
We're lucky to be alive, ma'am.
這不是靠運氣
Luck didn't have anything to do with it.
我們的飛行小組很優秀
We have a hell of a flight team.
你不能離開
It really stinks, you going.
機動部隊沒有我也一樣
Yeah, well, the Mobile Infantry will just have to get along without me.
我不懂 瑞哥 你接受了懲罰
I don't get it, Rico. You took your licks.
如果他們不想要你 可以把你踢走
If they didn't want you, they would have kicked you out.
嘿...
Hey...
我不該入伍 我害死人...
I joined up for the wrong reasons. I got a guy killed.
這就證明我沒有能力
I figure that kind of proves I don't have what it takes.
瑞哥 電話接通了
Rico, your call's going through.
去接
Take it there.
- 喂? 強尼 - 嗨 媽媽
- Hello? Oh, Johnny! - Hi, Mom.
比爾 快接電話 是強尼
B-Bill, pick it up. It's Johnny!
- 強尼? - 爸爸
- Johnny? - Dad.
- 你的制服呢? - 比爾...
- Where's your uniform? - Bill.
見到你真好
It's just good to hear from you.
你好嗎? 兒子?
How are you, son?
我不適合這 爸爸
It's not really working out here for me, Dad.
我在想...
I was thinking...
不知道我能不能回家
I was hoping it would be all right if I came home.
當然能 馬上回來
Well, of-of course. You should come home immediately.
對不起 我太傻了
I'm sorry. I've been an idiot.
別這麼說 你先回家...
Don't talk like that. You just come on home...
咱們再好好談談
talk things out.
我們很愛你 兒子
We love you, son.
- 那是什麼? - 好像要下雨
- My, what's that? - Looks like rain.
- 這時候? - 外面好暗
- This time of year? - Sure is dark.
大氣干擾導致...
Your transmission has been terminated...
通訊中斷
due to atmospheric interference.
請稍後再試
Please try your call again later.
再見了
Well, see ya.
嘿, 你就這樣退出...
Hey, you take that stroll down Washout Lane...
只證明一件事,強尼
you're only proving one thing,Johnny.
什麼事, 蒂絲?
What's that, Diz?
你沒有資格當公民
That you don't have what it takes to be a citizen.
∮ sound off  stand by ∮
什麼事?
What's happening?
嗨 發生什麼事?
Hey, hey, what's going on?
發生什麼事?
Wh-What's going on?
- 嗨 基頓 怎麼回事? - 戰爭 我們要去參戰了...
- Hey, Kitten, what's going on? - It's war! We're going to war!
這次的災難前所未有
The devastation we are seeing is unparalleled.
根據估計有數百萬人喪命 一座城市全毀
Judging from early estimates, millions dead, a city in ruins.
那是日內瓦嗎?
Is that Geneva?
強尼 是該死的大蟲攻擊我們
Goddam bugs whacked us, Johnny.
蟲族從大本營克蘭達夫星球...
The meteor was shot out of orbit by bug plasma...
發射電漿把隕石撞離軌道
that derived from Klendathu, the Arachnids'home planet.
這個曾被稱為拉丁樂園的城市片瓦不留
Nothing lives in what was once called the Latin Paradise.
強尼 那是我們...
Oh,Johnny, it's us.
布宜諾斯艾利斯完全消失
Buenos Aires has been wiped off the Earth.
...我們的家
That's home.
剛才聯邦委員會一致表決...
The Federal Council met moments ago and voted unanimously...
全體動員消滅蟲族大敵
for mobilization to destroy the Arachnid threat.
"8 764 608人死亡"
- 我是認真的 我要去 - 辛姆 你得留下來
- I'm serious. I'll go anywhere. - Forget it, Zim. We need you here.
- 我要打仗 - 只有一種方法能讓你去打仗...
- I want combat, sir. - The only way you're gonna see combat...
被降為二等兵!
is if you bust yourself to private!
- 明白? - 我明白 長官
- Get me? - Yes, sir, I get you.
- 長官 - 你要做什麼? 瑞哥
- Sir! - What do you want, Rico?
我要收回退出的要求
I wish to reconsider my request to drop out, sir.
你已經簽好表格
You already signed your 1240-A, son.
- 那是非法的 - 少校 我不該退出
- It wouldn't be legal. - Major, I know it was wrong.
我沒吸取教訓 反而又犯錯
I didn't learn from one mistake, and I made another, sir.
你做出決定
You made your decision, son.
長官 我全家都在布宜諾斯艾利斯
Sir, my family, my whole family, was in Buenos Aires, sir.
瑞哥 這是你的簽名嗎?
Is this your signature, Rico?
長官,是的 長官
Sir, yes, it is, sir!
看起來不像
Doesn't look like it to me.
- 去吧 二等兵 - 是的 長官
- Carry on, Private! - Yes, sir!
"聯邦電視網"
"戰爭"
看到布宜諾斯艾利斯市的殘骸先是悲痛
Out of the ashes of Buenos Aires comes first sorrow...
接下來是憤怒
then anger.
只有死蟲才是好蟲子
The only good bug is a dead bug.
聯邦委員會在日內瓦開會
In Geneva, the Federal Council convenes.
我們必須誓死...
We must meet the threat with our valour, our blood...
勇敢面對挑戰
indeed, with our very lives...
捍衛人類文明
to ensure that human civilization, not insect...
別讓蟲族永遠統治銀河系
dominates this galaxy, now and always!
狄恩元帥...
Sky Marshal Dienes announces plans...
向蟲族隕石來源...
for an offensive against Klendathu...
克蘭達夫星球宣戰
source of the bug meteor that destroyed Buenos Aires.
"你想知道更多嗎? "
聯邦科學家每天不斷研究新方法消滅蟲族
Every day, Federal scientists are looking for new ways to kill bugs.
一般的蟲族戰士很笨...
Your basic Arachnid warrior isn't too smart...
可是打斷它的一隻腳...
but you can blow off a limb...
它卻能保留八成戰鬥力
and it's still 86 percent combat effective.
有一個竅門：瞄準神經干 把它撂倒
Here's a tip.:Aim for the nerve stem, and put it down for good.
你想知道更多嗎?
人人都出力 你呢
Everyone's doing their part. Are you?
戰爭需要每個人貢獻力量
Die! Die! The war effort needs your effort...
家庭 工作和社區...
at work, at home, in your community.
"勝利倒數"
這堿O...
We now break net and take you live...
位於蟲族隔離區的...
to Fleet Battle Station Ticonderoga...
提康德魯加星際戰艦基地
deep inside the Arachnid Quarantine Zone...
英勇的星艦戰將準備出擊
where the men and women of the Federal Armed Services prepare to attack.
準備連線...開始
D XQ uplink on two, one. You're on.
這堥S人知道何時開始...
No one here in the AQZ knows exactly...
進攻克蘭達夫星
when the invasion of Klendathu will occur.
大家都在猜
But everyone's talking about it...
覺得也許是明天
and the talk says tomorrow.
看來機動部隊想大嚼蟲族
Here's a bunch of MI kids that look like they could eat bugs for lunch.
- 好吃 好吃 好吃 - 大兵
- Yum, yum, yum. - So, trooper,
你不怕大蟲嗎?
you're not too worried about fighting the Arachnids?
只要發射一枚核彈 大蟲就死翹翹
Hey, shoot a nuke down a bug hole, you got a lot of dead bugs.
希望全炸死之前 我能打死幾隻蟲
Am I right? I just hope it's not over before we get some.
- 得了 - 有人說蟲族生態...
- Okay, come on. - Some say the bugs were provoked...
遭到了破壞才對人類反擊
by the intrusion of humans into their natural habitat...
我們該和平共處不該對蟲族開戰
that a "live and let live policy" is preferable to war with the bugs.
我告訴你
Let me tell you something.
我是布宜諾斯艾利斯市人 我要消滅它們
I'm from Buenos Aires, and I say kill them all!
- 對 - 繼續
- Yeah! - Go on,Yeah!
- 對! - 對啊!
- Yeah! - Oh, yeah!
狠角色
Big bad bugs, huh?
咱們要去紋身
Hey, guys, we ought to get tattoos.
- 一起去吧 - 好
- Hey, let's all get cut together. - Yeah.
- 紋身幹嘛? - 什麼?
- What do I want a tattoo for? - Oh, what?
你的皮膚太嫩嗎?
Your skin's too pretty? Come on, everybody's doing it.
強尼
Hey,Johnny!
強尼·瑞哥
Johnny Rico.
卡門
Carmen?
稍息
Oh. At ease.
我休假 最好別戴軍帽
Guess I ought to lose the hat when I'm off duty.
- 嗨 蒂絲 - 卡門
- Hi, Diz. - Carmen.
我媽說得對
My mother was right about you.
你穿制服很好看
You look great in a uniform.
你也挺帥的
You look pretty good yourself.
你有什麼消息?
So, what do you hear?
布宜諾斯艾利斯有沒有人生還?
You know about anyone who made it out of BA alive?
我試著不多想
Most of the time I don't think about it.
假裝是別人的事
Like it happened to someone else.
可是突然覺醒時就哭個不停
Then it hits me, and I, uh, can't stop crying.
我們還活著 這值得高興
Well, we're still alive. Got to be happy about that.
你看到我好像不高興
You don't look very happy to see me.
我該高興嗎?
Should I be?
強尼
Johnny
現在不同 我們在打仗
It's different now. We're at war.
我們分開對你我都好
I mean, I think what I did was probably the best thing for both of us.
沒事吧 中尉?
Everything copacetic, Lieutenant?
山德 記得強尼嗎?
Zander, you remember Johnny.
我和山德是飛行搭檔
Zander and I are a flight team now.
艦隊最好的小組
Yeah, and we're best in the fleet.
我懂了
I get it.
這樣對你我最好
This is the part that's best for both of us.
- 別再裝了... - 強尼 等等
- Don't do me any more favours. - Johnny, wait.
算了 他是機動部隊
No, forget it, Lieutenant. He's Mobile Infantry.
他們只會殺人
See, when you're trained to kill...
不懂得禮貌
it just doesn't pay to be polite.
你對機動部隊有意見嗎?
You got something to say about the Mobile Infantry?
你聽得很清楚
I think you heard me.
你想打架嗎 二等兵?
You want to make something of it, Private?
我不跟軍官打架
Not with an officer. No, sir.
- 機動部隊不是蠢蛋 - 我就撇開官階
- The MI doesn't mint stupid troopers. - Well, let's disregard rank.
山德 別這樣
Zander, please.
聽到嗎? 這無關官階
Everybody hear that? Rank is not an issue here.
- 別這樣 - 他敢怎樣?
- Don't do this. - Come on. What's he gonna do?
來呀 臭大兵!
Come on, jarheads!
我要宰了你
Let go of me! Come on! I'm gonna kill you!
我要你好看
I'm gonna kill you! I'll kill you!
住手 快
Guys! Guys! Quit it! Come on! Come on!
- 他不值得 - 快 快
- He's not worth it! - Come on! Come on!
瑞哥 算了 機動部隊和艦隊一向不合
Forget it, Rico! Mobile Infantry and Fleet don't mix. Come on.
來吧 走吧
Come on, let's go.
臭大兵
Jarheads.
- 機動部隊萬歲 - 耶!
- Mobile Infantry rules! - Yeah!
痛死了
Oh, God, that hurts.
我有辦法讓你更痛
Hey, well, I got something that might hurt just a little bit more, buddy.
我們要打仗 一定會贏
Oh, yeah! We're gonna fight, and we're gonna win!
"死神降臨"
我是艦長
This is the captain speaking.
全體人員準備降落
All personnel prepare for drop.
倒數三分鐘
We are at D-minus three and counting.
我們是先鋒部隊
We are going in with first wave.
敵人最多
Means more bugs for us to kill.
徹底消滅敵區
You smash the entire area.
殺死所有長兩隻腳以上的東西
You kill anything that has more than two legs.
- 明白嗎? - 我們明白 長官
- You get me? - We get you, sir!
- 星球表面射出電漿 - 蟲族炮火
- Plasma, ma'am, from the planet. - Bug batteries.
軍事情報說威力應該不強
According to military intelligence, it'll be random and light.
- 部隊狀況? - 情況是...
- Drop status? - Drop is...
35%降落到地面
35 percent complete, ma'am.
慢慢來 副駕駛
Steady as she goes, Number Two.
記住你的訓練 你會活著回去的!
Remember your training, and you will make it back alive!
電漿威力很強 情報有誤
This isn't random or light. Someone made a mistake.
部隊全都降落了 女士
That's it. We're empty, ma'am.
有人犯了大錯
Someone made a big goddam mistake!
快往上飛
Break for high orbit!
走 走 走!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
強尼!
Johnny!
核彈待命
Rockets up!Rocket crew, move up!
- 核彈小組 利維 瑞哥... - 把它們炸死
- Nuke 'em! Levy! Rico! - Heat 'em up!
- 好了 - 發射
- Set. - Fire!
- 跟我來 - 上吧
- Follow me! - Let's go!
第一排 左翼!
First platoon, left flank!
分散! 第一 二班 跟我來
Split up! First and second squads, follow me.
第二班掩護 第一班跟我
Two, cover! One, with me!
一邊到另一邊
Along side! Side to side!
開火
Fire!
它們來了
Here they come!
- 王牌 我們該怎麼辦? - 我...不知道
- Ace, what are we doing? - Uh, I don't know.
- 我不知道 - 把它們全幹掉
- I don't know. - Kill them! Kill them all!
上呀
Come on!
找死嗎?
Come on! Come on! You want some?
我要你們死!
Here's some! Yeah!
吃子彈吧
Here's some of this!
我的天!
Oh, my God!
蘇傑米
Shujimi!
不 不 不!
No, no, no!
救命! 救命! 救命!
Help! Help! Help!
不! 天哪!
No! God!
快走吧
Let's get out of here!
撤退
Fall back!
怎麼了?
All units,What's going on? fall back to retrieval.
收到訊號嗎?
Repeat.You got com? All units...
全體撤退
fall back to retrieval.It's a general retreat!
- 回運兵船上! - 快!
- Back to the boats! - Come on!
快 我們走!
Come on, let's go!
這堿O被稱為
We've just landed here on what cap troopers...
大K星的戰場
are calling Big K...
第六機動部隊展開攻擊
with the 6th Mobile Infantry Division.
這醜陋的星球全是大蟲
It's an ugly planet, a bug planet.
威脅人類的生存...
A planet hostile to life as we...
救命啊!
Help me!
快向右
Squad right!
快走 快 快 快...
Come on! Go, go, go!
快離開這
Get out of here now!
- 小心點! - 小心你的側面! 小心你的側面!
- Watch your step! - Watch your flank! Watch your flank!
我們被擊潰
GXR, we're being overrun.
基頓 不!
Kitten, no!
哦 天哪
Oh, God!
哦 天哪 哦
Oh, God! Oh! Oh!
"聯邦電視網"
"一小時內十萬人喪命"
人類面臨空前危機
Crisis for humankind.
艦隊官員承認他們...
Fleet officials admit they underestimated...
低估蟲族的防衛能力
the Arachnids' defensive capability.
因為克蘭達夫星的慘劇
Accepting responsibility for Klendathu...
狄恩元帥引咎辭職
Sky Marshal Dienes resigns.
新任的元帥馬休...
His successor, Sky Marshal Tahat Meru...
宣佈她的戰略
outlines her new strategy.
我們必須
To fight the bug...
瞭解蟲族才能致勝
we must understand the bug.
我們絕對不能再重蹈克蘭達夫的覆轍
We can ill afford another Klendathu.
你想知道更多嗎?
聯邦科學家想...
Federal scientists struggle to explain...
解釋蟲族的軍事智慧
the intelligent military actions of the Arachnids.
蟲族經過三百代
When a colony reaches a certain size...
進化一定會變聰明
300 generations or something, it gets smarter.
- 聰明的蟲子? - 快...
- Insects with intelligence? - Now, wait...
你遇到過嗎? 難以置信...
Have you ever met one? I can't believe...
- 這種想法太荒謬了 - 請你聽我說
- I am hearing this nonsense. - Would you just wait a moment?
- 這是我聽過的最荒謬講話 - 可能 可能
- This is the most ridiculous conversation I have ever had. - Maybe... Maybe...
也許有一種蟲我們沒見過
there is some kind of bug that we haven't seen yet.:
領導階級 蟲族首腦
a leadership caste, a-a hive brain.
蟲族首腦? 蟲子也會思考? 才怪...
Brain Bugs? Frankly, I find the idea of a bug that thinks offensive!
星艦基地 楊羅傑號請求進入
Ticonderoga, this is Rodger Young requesting approach vector.
收到 楊羅傑號
Affirmative, Rodger Young.
座標l00951
One-zero-zero-niner-five-two.
歡迎回來
Welcome back.
我的天
My God.
怎麼會這樣?
How could this happen?
我們自以為比蟲族聰明
We thought we were smarter than the bugs.
"傷亡人數：308 563"
很奇怪 幾乎沒有人被俘
It's strange. There's almost no wounded at all.
蟲族不抓俘虜
Bugs don't take prisoners.
"強尼·瑞哥 陣亡"
哦...不...
Oh, no.
看
Look.
- 卡門... - 這
- Carmen... - See it? Right there.
- 他在那兒 - 我們會把他叫醒
- There he is. - Come on, we'll just wake him up.
嘿 強尼
Hey,Johnny! Hey!
- 瑞哥 - 強尼 醒醒
- Hey, Rico! - Hey,Johnny!
- 瑞哥 醒醒 - 你好嗎 小魚兒?
- Hey, Rico!Wake up! - How you doin', fish boy?
看 你死了
Hey, look. You're dead!
你陣亡了
Killed in action!
- 再過三天就能出來 - 三天
- Three more days. - Three days.
- 你出局了 - 再見
- And you're out. - Good as new. See you later.
回頭見
Bye.
新的部隊怎麼樣?
So what do you hear about our new unit?
硬漢部隊消滅的大蟲比誰都多
Roughnecks killed more bugs than any other outfit on Big K.
聽說中尉很嚴厲
Yeah, well, I hear their lieutenant's a real nutbuster.
士官長是誰?
Who's top kick?
你想當嗎?
You want the job, huh?
我不介意
I wouldn't mind.
我很介意
I would.
我只想出力
Just doing my part.
命令
Orders.
你的呢?
Yours?
你還到哪堨晶L仗?
Where you been besides Big K?
- 土星外環 西格瑪海灘 - 西格瑪海灘
- Outer rings, Zegema Beach. - Zegema Beach?
- 我一直想去那兒 - 好運氣
- I always wanted to go there. - Good luck.
- 不用去了 那堣ㄕs在了 - 聽說你們的中尉挺麻煩的
- It's not there any more. - So, I hear your lieutenant's a real nutbuster.
別批評中尉 他救我一命
No one talks about the lieutenant that way.
- 他救過我 - 也救過我
- He saved my life. - Mine too.
- 我也是 - 還有我
- Same for me. - Me too.
聽起來他人很好
Well, sounds like he's quite a guy.
你以為是誰救了你?
Who do you think saved your ass?
待命 立正
Stand by. Attention on deck!
新來的聽好
This is for you new people.
我只有一個規則
I only have one rule:
全力以赴 不能退縮
Everyone fights. No one quits.
明白嗎?
You don't do your job, I'll shoot you.
Do you get me?
明白 長官
We get you, sir!
- 歡迎到硬漢部隊 - 瑞斯加科的硬漢
- Welcome to the Roughnecks. - Rasczak's Roughnecks!
稍息 聽好
At ease. Listen up.
新的元帥有新的戰略
We got a new Sky Marshal and a new battle plan.
先一一消滅克蘭達夫...
We're gonna clean out the systems outlying Klendathu...
周圍的星球
one planet at a time.
明天攻擊探戈幽靈星
Tomorrow we hit Tango Urilla.
先進行轟炸然後再消滅殘留的敵人
After Fleet glasses the planet, MI mops up.
繼續吧
Carry on.
好吧 分散開來
All right. Spread out!
核彈小組 找到蟲穴就炸掉
Fire teams! You locate a bug hole, nuke it.
華肯 帶上弗洛斯和瑞哥
Watkins, shake out Flores and Rico.
收到 走吧
Copy that. Move out!
第一排 我們到山谷
First platoon, we're going for that ridge.
- 利維 跟我來 - 我要跟著瑞哥
- Levy, you're with me. - No, I'm in A Squad. I'm going with Rico.
給我閉嘴
Shut up and follow me!
你喜歡那個?
Hey, you like that?
吃屎的大臭蟲
Fungus-sucking sack of maggot puke!
華肯 它死了
It's dead, Watkins! It's dead!
死了就沒什麼可怕的
Ain't much to look at after you scrape them off your boot.
發現蟲穴 那兒
Bug hole. There.
炸掉它 瑞哥
Nuke 'em, Rico!
準備射擊
Fire in the hole!
我們受到攻擊 快來支援
Watkins, we're under heavy attack. Position M-4.
- 快去! - 快!
- Get over here! - Move!
- 你需要除蟲嗎 小姐? - 閉嘴 大兵
- You got a bug problem, ma'am? - Ah, stow it, trooper!
大甲蟲
Tanker!
- 媽的! - 快走吧
- Oh, shit! - Come on! Move!
趴下來
Get down!
跟我來
Come on!
通知救援隊
Stay down, sucker!
呼叫檢索
Call for retrieval.
- 醫官 - 好身手
- Medic! - Nice moves.
你在哪兒學來的?
Where'd you learn how to do that, soldier?
學校 你不記得嗎?
Back in school, sir. Don't you remember?
- 我是球隊隊長 - 瑞哥
- I was captain of the team. - Rico?
- 長官 - 我需要一名下士
- Sir. - I need a corporal.
在你陣亡之前你就當下士
You're it until you're dead or till I find somebody better.
謝謝你 長官
Thank you, sir.
- 好了 結束了 - 幹得好 下士
- All right, saddle up! Show's over. - Way to go, Corporal.
- 我要一名班長 - 不行 找搞砸過
- Hey, I need a squad leader. - Oh, no. No, I've been there and blew it.
我只想殺敵
I'm just here to fight.
你呢?
What about it, Diz?
看來就是我了
First sergeant, get your gear in section...Looks like I'm your girl, sir.
- 待會兒見 - 好
- Catch you later. - All right.
聽好
Listen up!
最好的士兵要有最好的享受
I expect the best, and I give the best!
這是啤酒
Here's the beer!
這是娛樂的東西
Here's the entertainment!
玩得開心點 這是命今
Have fun! That's an order!
這是我的
This one's for me!
謝了 中尉
Thank you, Lieutenant!
瑞哥
Rico!
你很會除蟲
You kill bugs good.
謝了
Thanks.
你在戰前認識中尉了吧
You knew the lieutenant before the war.
他為人如何?
What was he like?
他是個老師 什麼都懂
He was a teacher. Kind of like he knew it all.
總是帶著微笑
He always had this little smile.
現在他可笑不出來
Yeah, well, he don't smile much any more.
死這麼多人怎麼笑得出來
Yeah, well, I guess your bottle fills up real quick when your kids get smeared.
- 來吧 下士 - 我不跳舞了
- Come on, Corporal. - Ah, nah, I don't do that any more.
我記得你以前跳 來嘛
I remember when you used to dance. Come on.
我得下令嗎?
Do I have to pull rank?
抱歉 長官
Excuse me, sir.
瑞哥 你問過我的意見 想聽嗎?
Rico. You once asked me for advice. Want some now?
- 想 長官 - 中尉 總部來電
- Yes, sir. - Lieutenant, HQ is on the com.
看到好機會就要把握
Never pass up a good thing.
華肯 喝啤酒嗎?
Watkins. Beer?
瑞哥 跳完舞你打算幹嘛?
So, Rico, what are you doing after the dance?
有什麼好笑?
What's so funny?
世事真是難以預料
You know, just the way things work out.
我們終於在一起
We finally got together, Diz.
我愛你 強尼
I love you,Johnny.
瑞哥
Rico!
準備出動 歐文將軍在P星遇難
We're moving out. There's been a distress call from General Owen on Planet P.
穿好軍服 十分鐘後報到
So get your shit wired and report in ten minutes.
是的
Yes, sir.
誰在那?
Who's that with you?
弗洛斯 長官
Flores, sir.
二十分鐘吧
Make it 20 minutes.
是的 長官
Yes, sir.
二十分鐘?
Twenty minutes?
應該來得及
We can do it.
威士忌哨站 收到嗎?
Whiskey Outpost, do you copy?
這是硬漢部隊201 請回答
This is Roughneck 2-0 on tac three. Come in, please.
威士忌哨站 威士忌哨站
Whiskey Outpost, Whiskey Outpost,
這是硬漢部隊201
this is Roughneck 2-0 on tac three.
- 將軍有消息嗎? - 沒有 長官
- Any contact with General Owen? - No, sir.
連發送訊號都沒有
Not even the transponder signal.
被山谷擋住 到高處去
It's these canyons. Go to higher ground, Sergeant.
威士忌哨站
Whiskey Outpost, Whiskey Outpost...
這是硬漢部隊
this is Roughneck 2-0 on...
把你的槍給我
Sugar, your weapon.
救救我
Help me! Help me!
如果我落入敵手 你們也要殺了我
I'd expect anyone in this unit to do the same for me.
- 瑞哥 - 長官
- Rico. - Sir.
你是代理士官長 帶隊
You're acting sergeant. Move 'em out.
你們聽到了 快走吧
You heard the lieutenant! Saddle up!
天哪 有人血洗這地方
Jeez, someone really humped the bunk.
- 華肯 - 長官
- Watkins. - Sir.
檢查哨站 檢查死屍
Secure this compound. Police these bodies.
是的 長官 三個人上塔架 快點
Yes, sir. Give me three up on the tower, now!
這堜M那堳堨葴妗灟
Aye-aye.OP there! OP there!
檢查死屍
Away! Number Two, police up these bodies!
媕Y好臭
Stinks in there.Second squad, come with me on the gate!
- 瑞哥 - 是的 長官
- Rico! - Churchill, come with me! - Yes, sir.
我們需要救援 這地方都是大蟲
We need retrieval. This place crawls.
再找人修好通訊連線
Get somebody in the communications tent and get me an uplink.
是的 長官 蒂絲 去吧
Yes, sir. Diz, check it out.
- 知道了 - 指揮小組跟我來
- Roger. - Command group with me.
天哪
Ah, shit.
中尉
Lieutenant!
他們吃飯時遭到大蟲偷襲
Dirty bugs came in right while they were having chow.
它們從這媔i來
Yeah, this is where they got in.
中尉
Lieutenant.
你最好來看看
I think you're gonna want to see this.
什麼事 弗洛斯?
What do you got, Flores?
這地方真可怕
God, I hate this place.
你覺得這是什麼? 瑞哥?
What does that look like to you, Rico?
看來蟲鑽進他大腦
Looks like a bug was in his brain, sir.
它們吸光他大腦
They sucked his brains out.
打開來
Open that.
立正
Officer on the deck!
- 把將軍扶起來 - 走了?
- Pick up the general. - Gone?
安全嗎? 我們得快走
Is it safe? We've got to get out of here!
- 將軍 長官 - 我們...
- General!, Sir! - We've gotta...
謝謝你 謝謝你們
Thank God for you, all of you.
你們都是英雄 你們全都是
You're all gonna be heroes. Every last one of you.
- 把洞穴封起來 - 好的
- Close that hole. - Yes, sir.
我得逃命 聯邦秘密太重要
I had to evade capture. The security of the Federation was at stake.
我知道這地區的攻擊戰略
I have operational knowledge of what we're up to out here.
- 趕快連線 - 我正在努力
- Flores, I need that uplink. - Working on it, sir.
你看
Damn it.See?
它們鑽進你的大腦
They get in your mind.Battlegroup, this is Roughneck 2-0.
- 你看法利的下場 - 你知道嗎?
- Look, they did it to Farley. - Do you read?
它們鑽進你的大腦 逼你做事情
They got in his mind.Come in, Battlegroup. This is Roughneck 2-0.
它們逼法利聯絡指揮部
They make you do things. They made Farley call headquarters.
求救訊號是個圈套
The distress call was a trap.
它們也想知道我們的底細
They're just like us. They want to know what makes us tick.
摸清我們的弱點 這樣才能消滅我們
They want to know us, so they can kill us.
敵人會來襲 準備迎戰
Roughnecks, this is lead. Prepare for attack.
- 我們會被攻擊 - 救援機在哪呢?
- I repeat, we're gonna be attacked. - Where's the retrieval boat?
緊急狀況這是硬漢部隊 收到嗎?
Mayday. Mayday. This is Roughneck 2-0 to Battlegroup. Do you read?
哦 天哪
Oh, God!
天哪 我們死定了 懂嗎?
We're gonna die! Don't you understand?
我們都要死了
We're all gonna die!
第二陣容 跟我來!
Second squad, follow me!
- 克制一下自己 將軍 - 不行
- Control yourself, General. - I can't.
我不行 我做不到
I can't.
你乾脆殺死我
I wish you'd just shoot me.
中尉 他的腦袋不清楚
Lieutenant! He's just a little out of his mind, sir.
大蟲
Bugs! Bugs!
好吧
Die! All right.
準備好 全力開火
Warm it all up! Everything you've got!
- 快 - 大兵們 拚命吧
- Move! - Come on, you apes!
你們想一直活著吧?
You want to live forever?
- 這兒! - 我得到了蟲子!
- Here! - I got bugs!
開火吧
Fire at will!
飛蟲來襲
Incoming!
瑞哥 連線好了嗎?
Rico, where's my communication?
- 蒂絲 連線呢? - 再等一分鐘
- Diz, status on the uplink! - Give me a minute.
我們沒有一分鐘了
We don't have a minute!
艦隊 這是硬漢部隊
Battlegroup, this is Roughneck 2-0. We are under...
- 這堿O楊羅傑號 請說 - 我們受襲 請來救援
- This is Rodger Young. Go ahead. - We are under attack, sir. We need retrieval now!
P星球沒敵人
We have Planet Pas clear.
到處都是 快來接人
This place crawls, sir. We need pickup now!
- 說出位置 - 追蹤無線電訊號
- What's your position? - Come down on this transmission.
哨站? 太瘋狂了
Inside the outpost? That's crazy!
希望飛行員也瘋狂 完畢
Well, I hope you have a crazy pilot. Out!
中尉
Lieutenant!
救援機正趕來
Boat coming down, sir!
退進去 快撤
Fall back into the compound! Fall back!
全力抵擋敵人
Hold here! Hold what you've got!
彈藥快沒了
Running low!
我沒了
I'm out!
拿去 省著點
Here! Make 'em count!
掩護救援機 撤
Make cover fire! Fall back!
快 快 快
Move, move, move!
快登機 撤
Fall back to the boat! Haul ass!
- 我的天 - 哦
- Oh, my God! - Oh!
- 把他拉上來 - 快
- Get him outta there! Pull! - Come on!
瑞哥 瑞哥
Rico! Rico!
- 你知道該怎麼做 - 是的 長官
- You know what to do! - Yes, sir!
快下手 瑞哥
Do it, Rico!
- 嗯! - 蒂絲!
- Yeah! - Dizzy!
不!
No!
王牌 幫我拉住她
Ace, help me! Hold her down!
把她抬上機
Move! Get her into the boat!
蒂絲 千萬別死
Come on, Diz! Don't die on me!
把她抬走 快
Let's get her out! Let's go, let's go!
快上去
Let's go! Get aboard!
你們 快點...
Tower, let's go!
快來吧
Let's move it, tower! Run!
升空
Lift off!
- 強尼 我快死了 - 不
- Johnny, I'm dying-dying. - No.
不 你不會有事的 蒂絲
You're gonna be all right, Diz.
沒關係
It's all right...
因為我愛過你
because I got to have you.
別放開我
Johnny, don't let me go!
強...強...
Joh...Joh...
別放開...別放開...
Don't let... Don't let...
我要你知道
I think you should know...
你的朋友瑞哥在後面
your friend Rico is back there.
快通知艦隊轟炸這星球
Get on the com and tell Fleet to glass that rock.
誰下的命令 下士?
On whose authority, Corporal?
我的命令 任務由我指揮
That would be mine, sir. I assumed command of the mission.
楊羅傑號 我正式代表
Rodger Young, we have an official request...
機動部隊要求轟炸P星球
by the Mobile Infantry to commence bombardment of Planet P.
我以為你死了
I thought you were dead.
我沒死 很多戰友都死了
I'm not, but a lot of my troopers are.
不行
Negative on your request, DeRuyter.
元帥另有安排
The Sky Marshal has other plans for Planet P.
歡迎回來
Welcome back.
機動部隊負責死 艦隊負責飛
MI does the dying. Fleet just does the flying.
等等 有動靜了
Hold on. Something's up.
艦隊要進行大規模行動
Fleet's mobilized for a big operation.
立正
Attention on deck!
有人曾問我...
Once somebody asked me...
公民和平民...
if I knew the difference between a citizen...
有何不同
and a civilian.
我現在知道了
I can tell you now.
公民有...
A citizen has the courage...
捍衛人類安全的勇氣
to make the safety of the human race their personal responsibility.
蒂絲是我朋友
Dizzy was my friend.
她也是戰士
She was a soldier.
更重要的是
But more than that...
她是聯邦公民
she was a citizen of the Federation.
敬禮
Present arms!
放下
Order arms!
向左轉
Left face!
- 立正 - 繼續
- Officer on deck! - Carry on.
治葬隊伍解散
Burial detail dismissed.
稍息
At ease.
- 你好嗎 卡爾? - 我很好 卡門
- How are you, Carl? - Carmen, good.
強尼 我很遺憾你們被派到P星球
Johnny, I'm sorry it had to be your unit on P.
那次任務的生還率很低
That mission had a very low survival probability.
蟲族設下圈套 對吧?
The bugs laid a trap for us, didn't they?
證明它們有智慧
Elegant proof of intelligence, isn't it?
我早就猜到P星球上有蟲族首腦
We thought there might be a Brain Bug on P.
你早就知道卻派他們下去?
You knew, and you sent them anyway?
我們找不到首腦就不能進行攻擊
We couldn't afford to launch an operation if there wasn't one.
你不茍同 很遺憾
You don't approve. Well, too bad.
事關人類存亡
We're in this for the species, boys and girls.
它們數量眾多
It's simple numbers. They have more.
我每天都得決定...
And every day I have to make decisions...
派你這種人去送死
that send hundreds of people like you to their deaths.
難道你不知道嗎 中校?
Didn't they tell you, Colonel?
機動部隊專門送死
That's what the Mobile Infantry is good for.
希望你還能再戰
I hope you're ready for more.
我們要回去活抓首腦
We're going back to P to capture that Brain.
硬漢部隊隨時備戰
The Roughnecks are always ready, sir.
他們需要一名中尉 想當嗎?
I hear they need a new lieutenant. Want the job?
好的 等我陣亡你再換人
I'll take it, till I get killed or you find someone better.
全體人員報到
Attention. All personnel report to your stations.
75分鐘後降落
- Well... - Prepare for drop in 7 5 minutes.
你要小心 強尼
Take care of yourself,Johnny.
後會有期
I'll see you again.
立正
Officer on deck!
- 這些孩子是誰? - 支援部隊
- Who are all these kids? - We got reinforced.
多半是菜鳥
Most of them are fresh out of boot.
我們算是老兵
We're the old men, Ace.
新兵聽好
This is for all you new people.
我只有一個規則
I only have one rule:
全力以赴 不能退縮
Everyone fights. No one quits.
不盡力我就親自宰了你
If you don't do your job, I'll kill you myself.
明白嗎?
Do you get me?
明白 長官
We get you, sir!
- 歡迎加入硬漢部隊 - 瑞哥的硬漢部隊
- Welcome to the Roughnecks. - Rico's Roughnecks!
今天要進入蟲穴
Today we're gonna pay a visit to Bug City.
找一隻沒見過的大蟲
We're lookin' for a bug no one's ever seen before.
一隻聰明的蟲子
Some kind of smart bug.
它可能知道我們要去 來吧
And it probably knows we're comin'.
快! 跑 跑 跑
Come on! Run, run, run, run, run!
快閃躲
Evasive action.
準備進行超光速飛行
Get us clear for warp, Number Two.
五秒後 四...三...
Clear in five, four...
- 開始轉換超光速引擎... - 三...五
- Initiating star drive... - three...in five.
楊羅傑號被擊中 就快墜毀
This is Rodger Young. We're going down Repeat, this is Rodger Young.
- 快離開這 - 棄艦...
- Get out! We're going down. - Abandon ship! Come on!
卡門!
Carmen! Oh!
- 山德! - 這!
- Zander! - Here!
- 快趕去逃生艇 - 來吧
- We've got to get to the rescue deck! - Come on!
艦長
Captain!
快棄艦 這是命...
Abandon ship. That's an...
她死了 卡門 她死了
She's dead, Carmen. She's dead!
這兒
Go! Here!
跟我來
Follow me!
好了嗎?
Ready?
B63逃生艇 兩人在艇上
Life pod Bravo 6-3, two aboard.
搜尋降落點 掃瞄地形 這兒
Scanning for a landing zone! Checking terrain. Here!
- 你行嗎? - 小意思
- Can you handle that? - Piece of cake.
- 我們失去了楊羅傑號 - 你們在什麼位置?
- We've lost the Rodger Young! - What is your position?
經過確實 楊羅傑號墜毀
Flight Command, we have confirmation. The Rodger Young is down.
強尼
Oh.Johnny!
Johnny!
楊羅傑號遭擊毀
Rodger Young just burned up.
在救援
It's on the rescue net.
有沒有生還者?
Any survivors?
情況很糟
Well, they're getting tarred up there pretty bad.
B63逃生艇
Bravo 6-3, two aboard.
收到嗎?
Is anyone receiving?
- 有人收到嗎? - 收到
- Is anyone receiving? - Affirmative.
這堿O硬漢部隊
This is Roughneck 2-0.
訊號中斷 請重覆
You're breaking up. Say again.
- 卡門? - 請重複 信號中斷
- Carmen? - Say again. I'm losing you.
卡門!
Carmen!
準備降落
Prepare for landing.
反向推動器 三...
Retros in three...
二...一...啟動
two, one, fire!
卡門 卡門
Carmen. Carmen.
- 你沒事吧? - 嗯
- Hey, are you okay? - Uh-huh.
快下來
Get out. Get out.
這是硬漢部隊 收到嗎?
This is Roughneck 2-0. Are you receiving? Over. This is Roughneck 2-0.
- 卡門 你收到嗎? - 強尼 是你嗎?
- Carmen, are you receiving? -Johnny, is that you?
是我 你的位置和狀況如何?
It's me! Wh, what's your position and situation?
我們在蟲穴 地下二十米
We're in Bug City, 20 metres underground.
位置是...南42 東118
Position: south 42, east 118.
狀況...
Situation is...
重複 南42 東118
I repeat. South 4 2, east 118.
狀況呢?
What's your situation? Over.
卡門
Carmen.
狀況很危險
Situation is extremely hostile.
快派小隊救援
I need a squad to pull 'em out!
- 方向? - 西南方三公里
- Direction? - Three clicks, south by southwest.
小心
Look out!
- 怎麼辦? - 大伙聽到了
- What do you wanna do? - You heard the lieutenant.
救援隊 第三班跟我來
Rescue party! Third squad, come with me!
取消命令
Cancel that!
我們都知道她已經死了
You know as well as I do, she's already dead.
很遺憾 老兄
Sorry, buddy.
硬漢部隊 前進
Roughnecks, let's move.
好
All right.
它們為何不殺死我們?
Why didn't they kill us?
它們要活捉我們
They want us alive.
我們應該走這邊
We should go this way.
A連前往這方向
A Company's that way.
沒錯 可是卡門在這兒
Yeah, but Carmen's down there.
恕我直言 老兄 她已經死了
Hey, I hate to be rude, buddy, but word has it she's dead.
她還活著
She's still alive.
你怎麼知道?
How do you know?
- 別問我 我就是知道 - 聽著
- I don't know how I know, but I know. - Listen.
指揮官違反命令的...
You got command, but going off mission...
罪名很重
That's a serious offence.
你會被判吊刑
I think they hang you for that.
硬漢20部隊繼續前進
Roughneck 2-0, proceed on mission.
我要兩名自願者
I need two volunteers.
有一天
One day...
像我這樣的人...
someone like me...
會消滅你們...
is gonna kill you...
整個臭蟲族
and your whole fucking race.
你知道這是什麼嗎?
You know what this is?
你當然知道
Sure you do.
你是肥大的聰明蟲
You're some kind of big, fat, smart bug...
對吧?
aren't you?
來吧
Come on.
這是硬漢部隊
This is Roughneck 2-0.
蟲族首腦往西五區前進
Brain Bug sighted moving west of grid five.
快跑
Run!
快 快
Go! Go!
- 核彈給我 - 你想當英雄嗎?
- Give me the nuke! - You trying to be a hero, Watkins?
我想要除蟲
I'm trying to kill some bugs, sir!
你們快走
Get outta here! Get outta here!
快走吧
Move!
走吧
Come on! You like that? You like that? Come on!
想死嗎? 吃子彈吧
You want a little more?
You like that? You like that? You like that? You like that? You want a little more?
來呀 來呀
Come on! Come on!
走吧
Come on, come on, come on!
來吧 卡門
Come on, Carmen.
我們成功了!
We did it! We won!
- 怎麼回事? - 逮到它了
- What's going on? - They got it!
來呀
Come on!
它在想什麼 中校?
What's it thinking, Colonel?
它很害怕
It's afraid.
怕得要命
It's afraid!
- 快 - 好!
- Come on. - Yeah!
卡爾! 卡爾!
Carl! Carl! Hey!
你們還活著 很好
Well, look who's here. You made it. Good.
你教我的 是你教我去找卡門
It was you, wasn't it? You told me how to find Carmen.
這是機密
Well, that's classified.
我們三個在一起就...
You know, whenever the three of us are together...
能無往不勝
I feel like things might just work out.
希望你說的對 卡門
I hope you're right, Carmen.
我們逮到蟲族首腦 很快就知道它們的弱點
We've got one of their Brains now. Pretty soon we'll know how they think.
這樣一來就能擊敗它們
And then we'll know how to beat them.
有一天戰爭會結束
One day it will all be over...
大家會忘記這場奮戰的功臣
and everyone will forget that this was the moment.
回想之時
This is when it turned.
不是強大的艦隊或是犀利的武器
And it wasn't the mighty Fleet, it wasn't some fancy new weapon.
而是逮到蟲族首腦的辛姆教官
It was a drill instructor named Zim who captured a Brain.
- 好 - 辛姆?
- Yeah! - Zim?
辛姆逮到大蟲
Zim. Zim got the bug.
Zim got the bug, man!
- 幹得好 中士 - 謝謝你 長官
- Good job, Sergeant. - Thank you, sir.
- 我是二等兵 - 繼續 二等兵
- That would be private, sir. - Carry on, Private.
- 是的 長官 - 好
- Yes, sir! - Yeah!
蟲族首腦將透露什麼秘密?
What mysteries will the Brain Bug reveal?
科學家日以繼夜 探索它的奧秘
Federal scientists are working around the clock to probe its secrets.
一旦瞭解蟲族就能消滅它們
Once we understand the bug, we will defeat it.
我們有艦隊
We have the ships.
我們有武器
We have the weapons.
我們需要戰士
We need soldiers.
像絲黛克中尉這種戰士
Soldiers like Lieutenant Stack Lumbrezer.
抵達目標區 艦長
We're over the target area now, Captain.
- 還有卡門·艾邦妮茲艦長 - 我是艦長
- And Captain Carmen Ibanez. - This is the captain speaking.
準備降落
All personnel prepare for drop.
二等兵利維和瑞哥中尉
Soldiers like Private Ace Levy and Lieutenant John Rico.
給我上，你們這幫猿人，想他媽活
一輩子老不死嗎？
Come on, you apes! You wanna live forever?
我們需要你
We need you all.
服役就有公民權
Service guarantees citizenship.
"繼續奮戰"
"勝利在望"